Guide to the Samuel Brooks Morris Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Samuel Brooks Morris papers
1934-1940
SC0172
Morris, Samuel Brooks, 1890-1962.
8 Linear feet (6 boxes)
Correspondence, memos, notes, minutes, reports, bulletins, and maps from his work for the National Resources Committee and the National Resources Planning Board pertaining to the water flow of District 11 (Washington, Wyoming, Idaho, Montana, and Northern California). Correspondents include Donald M. Baker and F. H. Fowler.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, School of Engineering, 1977.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Separated Materials
A box of duplicate material has been removed from the collection.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Professor of civil engineering, Head of Civil Engineering Department (1935-1944) and Dean of the School of Engineering (1936-1945) at Stanford.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memos, notes, minutes, reports, bulletins, and maps from his work for the National Resources Committee and the National Resources Planning Board pertaining to the water flow of District 11 (Washington, Wyoming, Idaho, Montana, and Northern California). Correspondents include Donald M. Baker and F. H. Fowler.
Access Terms
Baker, Donald M. (Donald McCord), 1890-; Fowler, Frederick Hall.; Morris, Samuel Brooks, 1890-1962.; Stanford University. Department of Civil Engineering.; Stanford University. School of Engineering. Faculty..; United States. National Resources Committee. District Number Eleven.; United States. National Resources Planning Board.; Rivers --Northwest, Pacific.; Water-supply --Northwest, Pacific.
Collection Contents
- Papers, 1934-1940; Original Accession
  This series contains one sub-series: 1. Reports, 1936-1938.
  - NRPB-Water Regimen, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Water resources committee-NRC Dramag Basin Comm-meeting, 1939 Jun 21 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Weather Bureau, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Willamette V, Undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Willamette 7 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Willamete VIII (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Abel Wolman, Water Facilities NRPB, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bulletins and instructions, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - WPA Tabulations (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - WPA Working Copy (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - File Copy WPA Programs (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - FROM: WPA and PW (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Wyoming-Utah (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - NRC Reports, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Maps, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Maps (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Index-Photostat Cards (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - NRC-General Correspondence, 1936 May-Nov (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - NRC-General, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - NRPB-3 party agreement (maps, correspondence and info.), 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Misc. Reports and Correspondence, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1936 Aug (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - NRC: Eliot; Executive Officer/Drane; Secretary. Correspondence., 1935-1936 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - To Morris in field. Correspondence., 1936 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Correspondence-Employees, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Maps and Charts-Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Report: Study of the Resources of the Columbia River Basin in Wyoming. Snake River. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Report: Water Resources of Columbia River Basin in Wyoming. Snake River., 1938- (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Forest Service Report to Water Regimen Subcommittee. Facilities and Activities Related to Water in Pacific Northwest. Pacific Northwest Forest Experiment Station. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - U.S. Engineer Department. Report on Water Regimen Data for the Pacific Northwest., 1940 Jun 30 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Correspondence, circa 1940 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Bureau of Reclamation-Abstracts (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Bureau of Reclamation (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Bureau of Reclamation, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Snake River Drainiage, Report on Teton Reservoir and other Dam Sites, 1932 Nov (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Resettlement Administration, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Snake River Basin (Washington D.C.) (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Snake 4, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Snake general, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Snake IV, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Soil Conservation Service (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Planning consultants (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - NRC-Washington D.C., 1937-1938 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - NRC-Washington D.C.; Wolman, Eliot, etc., 1938-1939 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - National Resources Planning Board (correspondence and info.), 1939 Jul (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Wash Pac II, Undated (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Washington Pacific 2, Undated (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Washington Pacific (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - NRC-Washington State, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Washington State I (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - N.R.C. Washington State Planning Commission Ben Kiser, P. Hetherton, Ross Tiffany, Tyler, (correspondence), 1938-1939 Jun (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Wash. State-employment (correspondence between C. E. Dorisy, P. Hetherton, Putman, Fowler, etc.), 1935 Nov 1-1936 Sep 11 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Wash. State II (correspondence between J.D. Ross, P. Hetherton, R.G. Tyler and more), 1936 Aug 4-Nov 30 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Project list at Washington, 1936 Oct (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Oregon, 1938-1939 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Oregon, State Planning Board, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Nevada, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Montana, 1935-1936 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Montana, State Planning Board, 1937 Aug-Dec (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Oregon II (correspondence and Info.), 1936 Sep (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Oregon-Newspaper Clippings (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - NRC-Oregon, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Ore Pac III, Undated (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Oregon Pacific 3, Undated (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Oregon-Pacific Basin, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Oregon III (correspondence), 1936 Oct-Nov (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Oregon-employment (correspondence), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Pacific Northwest Regional (correspondence and info.), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - P.N.W. Regional II (correspondence), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - P.N.W. Regional III (correspondence), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - P.N.W. Regional IV (correspondence), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - P.N.W. Regional employment (correspondence), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Pacific Northwest (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - N.R.C. Land, 1939 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - California-Portland + cement assoc., 1936-1937 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - PWA forms (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Puget Sound, 1936 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Puget Sound 1, Undated (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Puget Sound I, Undated (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Applications-general (job info. applications etc.), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Army Engr. reports (correspondence), 1936 Aug-Sep 9 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Army (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Army, List of reports on rivers; Agrigultural Engineering, Bureau of (U.S. Department of Agriculture), 1936 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Baker Library record (misc.), Undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Bessey, Roy F., Pacific Northwest Regional Planning Commission, 1397 Aug-Sep (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Bessey, Roy F., Pacific Northwest Regional Planning Commission, 1937 Oct-Nov (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Bessey, Roy F., Pacific Northwest Regional Planning Commission, 1937 Oct-1938 Feb (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Bessey, Roy F., Pacific Northwest Regional Planning Commission (Folder 1), 1939 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Bessey, Roy F., Pacific Northwest Regional Planning Commission (Folder 2), 1939 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Bessey, Roy F., Pacific Northwest Regional Planning Commission, 1939 Jan-May (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Biological Survey, Undated (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Fowler memos (extra), 1936 (Box 7)
  - Columbia, Middle Columbia Basin Report (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Columbia, Middle-Public Work Administration Forms, Reports, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Columbia, Upper Columbia Basin Report (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Columbia, Upper-Public Works Administration Forms, Reports, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Columbia, Upper-Public Works Administration Forms, Reports, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Drainage Basin Study, records, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Drainage Basin Study, records, 1936 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Drainage Basin Study (tentative outline of revised report), 1936 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Drainage Basin Study (misc. tables, charts, memos), 1936 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Drainage Basin Study (tentative outline of revised drainage basin report #4), 1937 Sep 11 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Drainage Basin Study ("Drainage Basin Problems and Programs"), 1937 Oct 28 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Drainage Basin Study ("Revisions of Drainage Basin Problems and Programs"), 1937 Oct 28 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Drainage Basin Study ("Drainage Basin Problems and Programs"), second report, revisions to text, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Drainage Basin Study ("Drainage Basin Problems and Programs"), second report, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Drainage Basin Study ("Revision of 1937 report for Pacific Northwest Basins") (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Drainage Basin Study "Drainage Basin Problems and Programs" (Columbia, Snake), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Drainage Basin Study "Drainage Basin Problems and Programs" (Upper, Middle Columbia), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Drainage Basin Study "Drainage Basin Problems and Programs" (Lower Columbia, Puget Sound), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Drainage Basin Study "Drainage Basin Problems and Programs" (Washington and Oregon Coasts), 1937 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Drainage Basin Committee-Progress Report (Folder 2), 1940 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Drainage Basin Committee-Progress Report (Folder 1), 1940 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Jan-Nov
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Feb (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Mar (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Apr (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 May (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Jun (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Jul (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Aug (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Sep (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Oct (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - National Resources Committee Bulletin, 1939 Nov (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Reports, 1936-1938
    - 1936 Sep (Box 6)
    - 1936 Nov (Box 6)
    - 1936 Dec (Box 6)
    - 1937 Apr (Box 6)
    - 1937 May (Box 6)
    - 1937 Jun (Box 6)
    - 1937 Sep (Box 6)
    - 1937 Oct (Box 6)
    - 1937 Nov (Box 6)
    - 1938 Jan (Box 6)
    - 1938 Feb (Box 6)
    - 1938 Mar (Box 6)
    - 1938 Apr (Box 6)
    - 1938 May (Box 6)
    - 1938 Jun (Box 6)
    - 1938 Jul (Box 6)
    - 1938 Aug (Box 6)
    - 1938 Sep (Box 6)
    - 1938 Oct (Box 6)
    - 1938 Nov (Box 6)
    - 1938 Dec (Box 6)